Guide to the M. H. Abrams papers, 1912-2015.
Abrams, M. H. papers
- Series III. Correspondence
  - Correspondence regarding the Council of Scholars, Library of Congress, 1980-1994 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Miscellaneous, with two photographs of woman, 1983, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Richard Rorty correspondence, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Letter of course proposal, 1985 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Gerald Graff, "Critical Theory", 1989 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Stanley Fish, on Literary Theory anthology, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - General correspondence, 1991-1997 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Stephen Greenblatt, NAEL, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Shiro Wajima translations of essays, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Frank Lentricchia, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - General correspondence, 1997-2000 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Stanley Fish "Dinosaurs", 1999 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - General correspondence, 2006 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1952-1969 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Letter from Edgar Rosenberg, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1972, 1980-1985 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1990-1999 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 2000-2009 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 2010-2014 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - 100th Birthday Wishes, 2012 (Box 15, Folder 7-8)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, undated (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, labelled "from notable friends", 1939-1964 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Includes some certificates, and letters from Basil Willey, John Crowe Ransom, I.A. Richards, Karl Kryter, Robert Oppenheimer, WY Elliott, George Sabine, TG Bergin, Rene Wellek, and Carlos Baker among others. Also includes clippings and notes about Abrams' time in the Psycho-Acoustic Lab.
- Series IV. Publications
  - Subseries IV a. The Mirror and the Lamp
    - The Mirror and the Lamp suggested changes, correspondence, reviews, etc., 1950s-1960s (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Organic Aesthetics, discarded from final version of The Mirror and the Lamp, undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Notes towards a conclusion, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - German and Italian translation correspondence, 1969-1977 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence before and after publication, 1951-1970 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Subseries IV b. Natural Supernaturalism
    - Natural Supernaturalism outlines, correspondence, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Natural Supernaturalism suggested changes, correspondence, reviews, etc., 1970s (Box 3, Folder 89-90)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1971, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Suggestions, changes, expansions, undated (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Late comments and critiques, 1995-1997 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Japanese translations, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Chinese translations, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Subseries IV c. How to Do Things With Texts/Doing Things With Texts
    - How to do Things with Texts drafts and correspondence, 1978-1985 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, reviews, etc., 1987-1990 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Subseries IV d. The Fourth Dimension of a Poem and Other Essays
    - "Introduction: Spiritual Travelers in Western Literature" drafts and correspondence, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - "Kant and the Theology of Art" drafts and correspondence, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - "Keat's Poems: The Material Dimensions" for printing, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - "What is a Humanistic Criticism?" final copy, correspondence, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - "What is a Humanistic Criticism?" correspondence after publication, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - "What is a Humanistic Criticism?" last revised copy, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - "What is a Humanistic Criticism?" final copy, correspondence, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - "What is a Humanistic Criticism?", undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Offprints, 1967-2007 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Reading notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - "Spiritual Travelers in the Literature of the West" notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - "Kant and the Theology of Art" drafts and notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - "Hazlitt: the Mind of a Critic", 1983 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - "Keat's Poems: The Material Dimensions" draft, noted, undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - "The Language and Methods of Humanism" draft, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Subseries IV e. Essays
    - "Reply to Wayne Booth" manuscript, correspondence, 1975, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - "Art As Such: From Addison to Kant" correspondence and note cards, 1981-1984 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - "On Political Readings" drafts and correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - "Constructing and Deconstructing", 1981 (Box 4, Folder 9, 12)
    - Constructing and Deconstructing", 1979-1985 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - "Literary Criticism in America" draft and correspondence, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - "Art As Such: From Addison to Kant" correspondence and note cards, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - "Apocalypse: Theme and Variations", undated (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - "Coleridge, Baudelaire, and Modernist Poetics" correspondence, note cards, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - "A Note on Wittgenstein and Literary Criticism", 1974 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - "What's the Use of Theorizing About the Arts?" and Weitz's rebuttal, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - "What's the Use of Theorizing About the Arts?" reviews, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - "Romanticism: Apocalypse and Revolution" and "Apocalyptic Thinking", 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - "The Correspondent Breeze", 1961 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - "Coleridge's 'A Light in Sound'" copy for printing, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Reply to Wayne Booth, copy for printing, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Wordsworth catalogue foreward, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Paper? "The Dark Side of Romanticism", 1991 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - "Theories of Poetry" Princeton Encyclopedia of Poetry and Poetics, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - "The Cast of Consciousness" forward, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - "Behaviorism and Deconstruction: A Comment on Morse Peckham's 'The Infinitude of Pluralism'" notes, drafts, and correspondence, 1972-1978 (Box 5, Folder 69)
    - "The Transformation of English Studies, 1930-1995", 1997 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Academic Culture: AAAS, some papers, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - "On Reading Wordsworth’s 'Lyrical Ballads'" drafts and correspondence, 1987-1989 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Essays on 'Lyrical Ballads', undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - John Finch Memorial Essay, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - "Two Roads to Wordsworth" 2nd draft and final version, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - "The Pains and Pleasures of Scholarship", undated (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - A proposed table of contents for Eighteenth Century Critical Essays, undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Reviews, "The Correspondent Breeze", 1985 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Coleridge's dejections: Bald's MS, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Coleridge's dejections: chap, "The Great Romantic Lyric", 1960 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Coleridge's dejections: An Ode notes, outline, supplementary material, 1960 (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Coleridge's dejections: "The Poem Itself", 1961 (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Coleridge's dejections: An Ode full draft, undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Lycidas "Mantle Blue" correspondence, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - "English Romanticism: The Spirit of Age", 1964-1965 (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - "Structure and Style in the Greater Romantic Lyric", 1963-1965 (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Old Thesis: "Doctor Johnson's Spectacles", circa 1959 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - "The Beginnings of Modern English Criticism", undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Old Thesis chapter: "The Language of Poetry", undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Crane's Comments: "Unconscious Expectations in the Reading of Poetry", 1942 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Copies of published essays, undated (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Subseries IV f. Book Reviews
    - Crofts Classics. Pope comments, etc., 1954 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - On Coleridge, 1950s (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Read, The True Voice of Reason, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Brinkley: Coleridge on the 17th century; Whalley: Coleridge and Sara Hutchinson, 1950s (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Jean A. Hagstrum, Samuel Johnson's Literary Criticism, undated (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Wellek, History of Modern Criticism, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Ed. C.A. Zimansky, Critical Works of Thomas Rymer, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Wheelwright, Burning Fountain, circa 1950s (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Nahm, Artist As Creator, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Frye, Anatomy of Criticism, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Isabel Hungerland, Poetic Discourse, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Baker, The Sacred River, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Schneider, Coleridge, opium, and Kubla Khan; Reading notes, Hayter, Opium, 1950s, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Kermode, Romantic Image, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Tuveson, The Imagination as a Means of Grace, 1960s (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Owen Barfield, What Coleridge Thought, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Owen Barfield, History, Guilt, and Habit, 1980 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Review of David Bromwich, "Hazlitt: The Mind of the Critic", 1984 (Box 15, Folder 27)
- Series V. W.W. Norton Materials
  - NAEL IV: Lord Byron notes, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - NAEL IV: Wordsworth, Dorothy, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - NAEL Poems in Process, mss, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - NAEL recordings correspondence, 1986-1995 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Norton Audios, 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Poetry Recordings, Library of Congress, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Norton Sales Conferences notes, 1992, 1995, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Norton Anthology of Literature by Women 2nd edition correspondence, 1989-1991 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Norton Anthology of African American Literature correspondence and notes, 1987-1995 (Box 7, Folder 56-58)
  - Norton Anthology of Drama correspondence and notes, 1985-1986 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Norton Critical Editors correspondence, 1987-1992 (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - WW Norton Correspondence, 1967-1977, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 31-32)
  - WW Norton Correspondence, 1978-1995 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - WW Norton Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Towards NAEL 7th Edition, 1995-2002 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Towards NAEL 7th Edition, 1995-1998 (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Towards NAEL 7th Edition: Minor Authors, 1994 (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - NAEL 7th edition: Romantic Period, 1998 (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, 1962, 2000-2003 (Box 16, Folder 31-32)
  - Glossary of Terms, 2009-2010 (Box 16, Folder 33)
- Series VI. Harvard Psycho-Acoustic Laboratory
  - The Problem of Selecting and Training Personnel for Communication in Intense Noise, November 10 ,1942 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Studies on the Effect of Noise on Speech Committee, November 25, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Psycho-Acoustic Lab Reports, 1942-1946 (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Harvard Defense Group, 1940-1941 (Box 16, Folder 36)
  - Vocabularies for Military Communication in Noise, August 1943 (Box 16, Folder 37)
  - Collected Informal Communications on the Basic Audibility of English Words for use as Oral Codes, Alphabetic Equivalents, etc., July 9, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 38)
  - Auditory Tests of the Ability to Hear Speech in Noise, September 1, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Speech in Noise: A Study of the Factors Determining its Intelligibility, September 1, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Certificate from the War Manpower Commission, and letter from Abrams to committee, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 7)
- Series VII. Reprints
  - Richard Lederer, "The World According to Student Bloopers", undated (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Reprints of "The Milk of Paradise", with correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Articles on Analytic Philosophy of Criticism, circa 1949-1978 (Box 11, Folder 3-4)
  - Derrida reading notes and xeroxes, 1970s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Deconstruction notes, correspondence, and xeroxes, 1970s-1980s (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - J Hillis Miller reading notes, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Skepticism notes, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Pluralist history, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - How To Do: Xeroxes, Fish and Bloom, 1970-1979 (Box 11, Folder 10-11)
  - Authors: A, 1943-1970 (Box 11, Folder 12-13)
  - Authors: B, 1927-1970 (Box 11, Folder 14-16)
  - Authors: C, 1949-1978 (Box 12, Folder 1-2)
  - RS Crane: Locke Theory, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - RS Crane: "The High Priori Road", 1955 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - RS Crane; Gray's "Elegy", 1950 (Box 12, Folder 5-6)
  - Authors: D, 1948-1971 (Box 12, Folder 7-8)
  - Authors: E, 1938-1972 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Authors: F, 1948-1978 (Box 12, Folder 10-11)
  - Freccero, "Donne's 'Valediction: Forbidding Mourning'", 1963 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Authors: G, 1951-1981 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Authors: H, 1947-1998 (Box 12, Folder 14-16)
  - Authors: I, 1955-1969 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Authors: J, 1952-1975 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Authors: K, 1949-1975 (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
  - Authors: L, 1905, 1937-1996 (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
  - Authors: M, 1942-1992 (Box 13, Folder 7-8)
  - Authors: Mc, 1942-1974 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Authors: N, 1951-1964 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Authors: O, 1954-1989 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Authors: P, 1951-1991 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Authors: R, 1955-1980 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Authors: S, 1936-1979 (Box 14, Folder 2-4)
  - Authors: T, 1909, 1912, 1943-1982 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Authors: V, 1968-1985 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Authors: W, 1944-1994 (Box 14, Folder 7-9)
  - Authors: XYZ, 1960-1997 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Harvard University, "Examination Papers in the Bible, Shakespeare, Ancient and Modern Authors…", 1932-1941 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - "On the Application of the Terms Poetry, Science, and Philosophy", undated (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Life, May 2, 1969 (Box 20)
- Series VIII. Personal
  - Daily planners, 1978-1983, 1989-1993 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Wordsworth Collection buying fund, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Biographical information, 1952-2014 (Box 15, Folder 14-16)
  - Photos of Abrams, undated (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Poetry reading, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Photograph of Abrams with the Obamas, circa 2014 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - The Harvard Freshman Red Book, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Coleridge in Malta notebook, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Passports for Meyer and Ruth and travellers checks, 1986, 1996, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - International certificates of Vaccination, 1960-1994 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Navy Department identification booklet, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Daily planner, 1975-1976 (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Photographs of young woman, circa 1970s (Box 17, Folder 26)
  - Harvard Class Album, 1934 (Box 20)
  - Various award invitations, 1963, 1973, 1988, 2001 ,2013 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Doctor of Letters degree from Western Maryland College, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Doctor of Humane Letters degree from Carleton College, 2003 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Doctor of Humane Letters degree from Northwestern University, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Doctor of Humane Letters degree from University of Chicago, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Doctor of Humane Letters degree from University of Rochester, 1978 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Doctor of Humane Letters degree from Le Moyne College, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Long Branch High School distinguished alumni hall of fame inductee certificate, 1993 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Doctor of Humane Letters degree from University of Chicago presentation photo, 1982 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Harvard Bachelors degree, 1934 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - MLA of America James Russell Lowell Prize, 1972 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - McDaniel College, 2002 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Doctor of Humanities degree from Yale University, 2007 (Box 20)
  - National Humanities Medal certificate, signed by Barack Obama, 2014 (Box 20)
  - Keats-Shelley Association of America Distinguished Scholar Award, 1987 (Box 21)
  - Coin purse, undated; MU-1730 (Box 22)
  - Long Branch High School class ring, 1930; MU-1731 (Box 22)
  - Harvard Phi Beta Kappa pin, 1934; MU-1732 (Box 22)
  - Long Branch High School class ring, Ruth Abrams, 1934; MU-1733 (Box 22)
  - Cornell Spirit of the Red pin, 1999; MU-1734 (Box 22)
  - Harvard medal, 1934; MU-1735 (Box 22)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences medal, 1984; MU-1736 (Box 22)
  - Long Branch High School highest general average pin, 1930; MU-1737 (Box 22)
  - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences fellow award, 1967-1968; MU-1738 (Box 22)
  - National Humanities Medal and pin, 2013; MU-1739 (Box 22)
  - 100th birthday signature book, 2012 (Box 23)
  - Yale honorary doctorate, 2007 (Box 23)
  - The American Academy of Arts and Letters Academy Membership certificate, 2001 (Box 23)
- Series IX. Miscellaneous
  - "Prospectus" manuscript typescripts of thesis MSS, photostats of MSS, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Schelling: "De Prima Malerum Humanorum Origine…" translation (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Christopher Smart: "A Song to David" Reading Notes (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Addison and Heterocosmic model, Art As Such notes (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Art As Such reading notes, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Art As Such xeroxes, A-L, various (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Art As Such xeroxes, M-Z, various (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Secondary literature on Schiller and Ferguson bibliography, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Stuart Alan Curran, "The Nuptial Metaphor in Christian Thought Down Through the End of the Fourteenth Century", 1964 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Great Book Reviews anthology notes, undated (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Committee for National Humanities, 1973-1974 (Box 7, Folder 65-66)
  - National Humanities Center planning and position papers, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - National Humanities Center, 1974-1986 (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - National Humanities Center Board of Trustees, 1976-1988 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - National Humanities Center memberships, 1977-1993 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Committee on Humanities Center, 1953-1961 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - School of Criticism, Northwestern, 1980-1982 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - AAAS Prize Committee, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - The Council of Scholars of the Library of Congress, 1983, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Articles and clippings about MH Abrams, 1960-2014 (Box 15, Folder 10-13)
  - 3 letters to Ruth Abrams, 1966, 1985, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Miscellaneous programs and invitations, undated (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - John Keats "Autumn" printouts, undated (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Kendal Trails Committee, 1997-2000 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Harvard 45th reunion class directory, 1979 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Work Agreements, 1985, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - English Department Directories, 1994, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Publications, etc. Annual Reports, 1970-1983 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Goldwin Smith Hall Dean's offices relocation, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Department directories, 2009-2010 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - D. Riddiford, Conceiving and Reconceiving Romanticism, with letter, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 24)
  - Cornell Voucher book, undated (Box 17, Folder 25)
  - Reading notes on note cards, undated (Box 18-19)
  - High Romantic Argument Symposium fliers and letter, 1978, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Oral history interview with Mike Abrams, conducted by Jonathan Culler and Neil Hertz., February 18, 2008; CD-437
    Recorded in the home of Mike Abrams, Kendal of Ithaca, also present Corey Earle. Topics include his experiences, the Norton Anthology, Cornell English Department history, and others.
SEPARATED MATERIAL
Books catalogued individually
Harvard College Class of 1934 Thirty-fifth Anniversary Report, 1969 Signed by Abrams.
Harvard University Summaries of PhD Theses 1940, 1942
Jason Grist Chasing Fall Colored Leaves, 1999 Signed with note to Abrams.
Susanne Klingenstein Enlarding America, 1998 Signed with note to Abrams.
David Lodge Small World, 1984 Includes letter from Lodge.
Thomas Pynchon Mason and Dixon, 1997 Signed with note to Abrams.
Frank Robinson Soft Applause for the Day, 2011 Signed with note to Abrams.
Alfred Kizin An American Procession, 1984 Signed with note to Abrams.
Ruth F. Boorstin Love is Not Because, 1998 Signed with note to Abrams.
Sharon Hamilton Essential Literary Terms, 2007 Includes letter from Hamilton.
Thomas Mann Tonio Kroger, 1947 Signed with note to Abrams.
Mihail Lermontov, translated by Vladimir Nabokov A Hero of Our Time, 1958 Signed by Nabokov.
Oxford Book of English Verse, 1927
Larry Berger, Lynn Harris Tray Gourmet, 1992
Shakespeare Tragedy of Othello, 1921 Heavily annotated by Abrams
Shakespeare King Henry the Fifth, 1921 Heavily annotated by Abrams
Shakespeare Tragedy of Hamlet, 1921 Heavily annotated by Abrams
Shakespeare The Winter's Tale, 1921 Heavily annotated by Abrams
Ernest Rhys Thomas Dekker, 1887
Thomas Malory Le Morte Darthur, 1929
Meyer H. Abrams The Milk of Paradise, 1934 Signed by Abrams.
Meyer H. Abrams The Milk of Paradise, 1971
Meyer H. Abrams The Milk of Paradise, 1962
Meyer H. Abrams The Fourth Dimension of a Poem and Other Essays, 2012
Meyer H. Abrams The Correspondent Breeze, 1984
Meyer H. Abrams Natural Supernaturalism, 1971
Meyer H. Abrams Doing Things with Texts, 1989
Meyer H. Abrams The Norton Anthology of English Literature, vol. 1-2, 1968